Philip J. Klass Collection 1948-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.59
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Periodicals, 1967-2000; 11 lin. feet
  - Skeptics UFO Newsletter (SUN) Vol. 1-30, 1989-1994 (Box Series VI-18)
  - Skeptics UFO Newsletter (SUN) Vol. 31-60, 1995-1999 (Box Series VI-18)
  - Skeptics UFO Newsletter (SUN) Vol. 70, 2002 (Box Series VI-18)
  - Skylight Aktuell / International, 1990 (Box Series VI-18)
  - South Shore Skeptic, 1991 (Box Series VI-18)
  - Space World, 1977 (Box Series VI-18)
  - Staf Beacon, 1997 (Box Series VI-18)
  - SUFOI Newsletter, 1990 (Box Series VI-18)
  - Tahtiviesti, no date (Box Series VI-18)
  - Treat V, 1993 (Box Series VI-18)
  - UFO, 1988-1995 (Box Series VI-19)
    - UFO, 1988 (Box Series VI-19)
    - UFO, 1989 (Box Series VI-19)
    - UFO, 1990 (Box Series VI-19)
    - UFO, 1991 (Box Series VI-19)
    - UFO, 1992 (Box Series VI-19)
    - UFO, 1993 (Box Series VI-19)
    - UFO, 1994 (Box Series VI-20)
    - UFO, 1995 (Box Series VI-20)
  - UFO (Japan), 1992 (Box Series VI-20)
  - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1992-1999 (Box Series VI-20)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1992 (Box Series VI-20)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1993 (Box Series VI-20)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1994 (Box Series VI-20)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1995 (Box Series VI-20)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1996 (Box Series VI-20)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1997 (Box Series VI-21)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1998 (Box Series VI-21)
    - UFO Newsclipping Service, 1999 (Box Series VI-21)
  - UFO Rivista Di Informatione Ufologica, 1988-1995 (Box Series VI-21)
  - UFO Rivista Di Informatione Ufologica, 1996-1998 (Box Series VI-21)
  - UFO Times, 1995 (Box Series VI-21)
  - UFO Universe, 1990 (Box Series VI-21)
  - Ufologist, 1992-1994 (Box Series VI-21)
  - VSD, no date (Box Series VI-21)
  - West Virginia UFO Newsletter, 1995-1996 (Box Series VI-22)
  - X Factor, 1997 (Box Series VI-22)
- Series VII. Audiovisual Materials, 1980-1998; 5 lin. feet
  Video and audio tapes relating to UFO and SDI programs that Klass either recorded purchased or from television. The audio tapes include recordings of lectures and radio/TV interviews by some of the UFO movement leaders (such as James E. McDonald and J. Allen Hynek), in addition to interviews Klass conducted as part of his own investigations. Finally, most of the printed materials which Klass donated have been transferred to the Printed Materials department.
  Due to copyright restrictions, material in this series cannot be copied.
  A photograph of Klass demonstrating a manner in which UFO photography can be produced is included at the end of this series.
  - 1990 Montreal UFO Incident, 1995 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Alien Abductions: Alternative Explanations and Guidelines, 1993 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Alien Autopsy (Commercial Video), unknown (Box Series VII-1)
  - Alien Autopsy-Fact or Fiction?, 1995 August 28 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Alien Autopsy [Fox Network, 2nd showing], 1995 September 4 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Alien Autopsy Film (Roswell): FUJI TV, unknown (Box Series VII-1)
  - Alien Autopsy: The Uncut Footage, unknown (Box Series VII-1)
  - Alien Encounters from New Tomorrowland, 1995 March (Box Series VII-1)
  - Are We Alone [CBS-48 Hours], 1994 April 20 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Are we Alone? (CBS news), 1996 December (Box Series VII-1)
  - Are we Alone? (in the Universe), 1992 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Area 51: Interview with an Alien, 1998 January 20 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Arthur C. Clarke UFOs; HBOX Undercover Special; Gulf Breeze Case (Unsolved Mysteries); Billy Meier, 1985; 1990 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Beyond Science? (Scientific American Frontiers), 1997 November (Box Series VII-1)
  - Beyond the Line: UFO Abduction Episode, 1990 March 18 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Crop Circles + Home Video of UFO, 1991 September (Box Series VII-2)
  - Crossfire (CNN), 1994 April 29 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Danger in our Skies: New UFO Threat / We are the Aliens, 1999 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Debunking "Alien Autopsy" [ABC-TV 20/20], 1997 April 4 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Don Berliner: Crash at Corona [Hartford Cty. Aston. Society], 1992 October 10 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Dr. John Mack and "Abductees" CNN "Sonya Live", 1994 April 28 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Encounters: The UFO Conspiracy, 1994 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Encounters: The UFO Conspiracy [FOX TV], 1994 February 22 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Extraterrestrial Contact: Proof Beyond a Reasonable Doubt, 1998 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Fifth Annual Ozark UFO Conference #9-Abductee Panel and Expert Panel, 1993 April (Box Series VII-2)
  - Fire in the Sky: Travis Walton / Mike Rogers [Larry King Live and Hard Copy], 1993 March 12 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Flying Saucers are Real! Vol. 1, 1996 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Flying Saucers are Real! Vol. 2, 1996 (Box Series VII-2)
  - Interview with AFOSI Agent Richard C. Doty on 1980 Kirtland AFB UFO Incident, 1988 August (Box Series VII-3)
  - Interview with the "Alien Santili Cameraman"; KNBC L.A. Implants Removed from People; KNBC L.A. Area 51 Secret Base; KTLA L.A. UFO Abductions and E.T.s; KTLA L.A. Area 51, 1997 May (Box Series VII-3)
  - Intruders, 1992 May (Box Series VII-3)
  - Intruders [CBS TV], 1992 May (Box Series VII-3)
  - Jackie Mason Show #23, unknown (Box Series VII-3)
  - Jerry Springer: Aliens!, 1992 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Kidnapped by UFOs? (NOVA), 1996 February 27 (Box Series VII-3)
  - KTVU (Oakland) UFO Seriess, 1996 November (Box Series VII-3)
  - Larry King Live, 1995 August 4 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Larry King Live, 1995 August 4 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Larry King Live-Roswell, 1991 July 1 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Maury Povish Show-Budd Hopkins + 6 "abductees", 1996 September (Box Series VII-3)
  - Misc. TV, 1980-1990 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Misc. UFO Chit Chat, 1993 August 8 (Box Series VII-3)
  - Morton Downey, Jr. TV Show on UFOs, 1988 September (Box Series VII-4)
  - Mysterious Skies, 1999 February (Box Series VII-4)
  - NASA and UFOs, 1992 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Rolanda Talk Show, 1994 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Ron Reagan Show: UFOs, 1991 December (Box Series VII-4)
  - Roswell (Movie), 1994 July 31 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Roswell (Showtime Movie), 1994 July 31 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Roswell / Alien Autospy (Japanese TV), 1996 April (Box Series VII-4)
  - Roswell: Paul Davids' Rebuttal to USAFs 1994 Report, unknown (Box Series VII-4)
  - SCAM Cameraman Interview, 1996 December (Box Series VII-4)
  - Science Frontiers-#1 UFO, #2 Close Encounters of the Fifth Kind, 1995 April 8 (Box Series VII-4)
  - SDI: The Technical Challenge, 1986 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Secrets and Mysteries: UFOs; UFOs: Ascientific Enigma [MUFON], 1987; 1985 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Sightings: The UFO Report, 1991 October 18 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Soviet UFOs: Hard Copy; Montel Williams: UFOs, 1991 May 27; 1993 December (Box Series VII-4)
  - Special on UFOs, Albuquerque, 1992 July 9 (Box Series VII-4)
  - Star Wars [PBS], 1986 April 22 (Box Series VII-5)
  - Straight Talk on UFOs, 1989 September 7 (Box Series VII-5)
  - The Mexican UFO's [MUFON Symposium], 1998 (Box Series VII-5)
  - The Quality of the Messenger: An Inside Look at the Quest for Credible Information in the Field of UFO Research, 1993 (Box Series VII-5)
  - The Secret KGB UFO Files, 1998 April 13 (Box Series VII-5)
  - The UFO Cover-up? Live from Area 51 [TNT Larry King Special], 1994 October 1 (Box Series VII-5)
  - The Uninvited, 1998 (Box Series VII-5)
  - TOPX: Abducted by UFOs, 1996 September (Box Series VII-5)
  - UFO "Mish-Mash", unknown (Box Series VII-5)
  - UFO-the Untold Stories, 1994 (Box Series VII-5)
  - UFO-The Untold Stories Continue, 1996 (Box Series VII-5)
  - UFO Abductions: Oprah Winfry, John Mack, 1994 April 18 (Box Series VII-5)
  - UFO Diaries (6 Tapes), 1996 (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO Incident (Betty/Barney Hill UFO abduction) NBC-TV, 1975 October 20 (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO Phenomenon, 1995 (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO Secret: The Roswell Crash, 1993 (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO TV: Larry King, Current Affair, 1992 (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO's Are Real, 1993 (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO-Abductions Lecture by Budd Hopkins, unknown (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO-Abductions: Dr. John Mack, 1994 April (Box Series VII-6)
  - UFO: The Hidden Truth (4 Volumes), 1996 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOlogy at the Turning Point: William L. Moore, Budd Hopkins, Stanton Friedman, 1989 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs-The Best Evidence, unknown (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs [Japanese TV], 1995 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs Down to Earth, 1997 January 5 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs: Fact of Fantasy?, 1991 March 11 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs: Have we Been Visited? II, 1998 February 22 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs: Danger in the Skies, 1998 April 6 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs: Fact or Fantasy?, 1991 March 11 (Box Series VII-7)
  - UFOs: Miracle of the Unknown (2 tapes), 1994 (Box Series VII-7)
  - Unsolved Mysteries, 1994 September (Box Series VII-8)
  - Unsolved Mysteries-Gulf Breeze Update; Vancouver UFO Movie, 1990 (Box Series VII-8)
  - Unsolved Mysteries; Prime Time: Russian UFOs; The Unexplained, 1991; 1994; 1996, 1997 (Box Series VII-8)
  - Visitors from the Unknown, and UFOs are real, 1991 and 1979 (Box Series VII-8)
  - War in Space [PBS]; Star Wars [NBC], 1983; 1984 (Box Series VII-8)
  - Where are all the UFOs?, 1996 May 12 (Box Series VII-8)
  - Whitley Strieber: Larry King Live, 1988 September (Box Series VII-8)
  - "Technology Development Overview" Mr. John Gardner-Second Annual SDI Briefing, 1985 (Box Series VII-9)
  - 15th Interplanetary Conclave of Light-Jerry Clark Speaker, n.d. (Box Series VII-9)
  - Budd Hopkins, "Patterns of UFO Abductions", 1999 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Directed Energy Weapons, AAAS 1988 Annual Meeting-Boston (3 tapes) (Box Series VII-9)
  - Dr. John Mack: MUFON-93, 1993 July 3 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Excerpts from Robt. Carr Interview (From WWDC), 1974 November (Box Series VII-9)
  - George Knapp: UFOs in Russia, MUFON-Austin, 1994 July 9 (Box Series VII-9)
  - John Mack SSE, 1999 June 5 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Karl Pflock / KOB (2 tapes-audio), 1995 March 28 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Karla Turner: MUFON-94 / Austin, "UFO, 1994 July 9 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Mark Scott / Phil Klass, 1996 November 1 (Box Series VII-9)
  - MUFON 1996 Symposium, Medical and Surgical Aspects of UFO Abductions, Roger K. Leir (Box Series VII-9)
  - MUFON 1996 Symposium, Studying Intrusions from the Subtle Realm..., John E. Mack (Box Series VII-9)
  - MUFON-93: Linda Moulton Howe + Final Q&A, 1993 July 4 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Roswell Int'l UFO Mueum Lecture Seriess-Lt. Col. Philip Corso and Wm. Birnes, 1997 July 5 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Roswell UFO Encounter '97 Lecture Seriess-Budd Hopkins, 1997 July 4 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Roswell UFO Encounter '97, Lecture Seriess-Robert O. Dean, 1997 July 5 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Roswell: Art Bell Radio Talk-Show with PJK / Stan Friedman, 1993-1994 ? (Box Series VII-9)
  - SSE David Jacobs, 1999 June 4 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Stan Friedman / WXYZ, Host: Mark Scott, 1997 February 5 (Box Series VII-9)
  - Steven Greer, New Age Renaissance Fair, San Jose, 1997 November (Box Series VII-9)
  - The UFO Experience, Dr. Robert Wood and Ryan Wood, "Cosmic Watergate: New Evidence of Alien, 1998 October (Box Series VII-9)
  - The New MJ-12 Papers, n.d. (Box Series VII-10)
  - Philip Klass debunking existence of unidentified flying objects through demonstration of UFO photograph faking techniques., 1967; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Klass holding a disk in the air, showing how photography can be faked.
- Series VIII. Annotated Publications, 1975-1998; 1 lin. feet
  Contains unpublished works by other authors, gray literature, and galley proofs for Klass' book "The Real Roswell Crashed-Saucer Coverup." Correspondence and other items once folded into published works have been removed and placed in folders in this series, with the published works themselves transferred to the Printed Material Department for storage. For a complete listing of published titles, see the separation report above.
  - Bartholomew, Robert E. "UFOlore: A Social Psychological Study of a Modern Myth in the Making" #1, 1988 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Bartholomew, Robert E. "UFOlore: A Social Psychological Study of a Modern Myth in the Making" #2, 1988 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Bartholomew, Robert E. "UFOlore: A Social Psychological Study of a Modern Myth in the Making" #3, 1988 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Bullard, Thomas E. "The Sympathetic Ear: Investigators as Variables in UFO Abduction Reports", 1996 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Ecker, Frances Anne. "Grey Matter", 1983 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Gersten, Peter A., "The Ultimate Secret" Vol. 1, 1987 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Klass, Philip J. Review of Out There by Howard Blum, 1991 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Klass, Philip J. "The Real Roswell Crashed-Saucer Coverup" [Uncorrected Galleys], 1997 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - "Jim Ragsdale Story: A Closer Look at the Roswell Incident", 1996 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - "Unusual Personal Experiences", 1992 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Fawcett, Lawrence and Barry J. Greenwood. Clear Intent, 1984 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Haines, Richard F. UFO Phenomena and the Behavioral Scientist, 1976 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Hopkins, Budd. Intruders, n.d. (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Hynek, J. Allen and Jacques Vallee. The Edge of Reality, 1978 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Meaden, George Terence. The Circles Effect and Its Mysteries, 1979, 1985, 1989 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Pope, Nick. The Uninvited, 1997 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Randle, Kevin D. The October Scenario, 1988 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Rhea, John. SDI: What Could Happen, 1988 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Seller, Charles E. UFO, n.d. (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Sheaffer, Robert. UFO Verdict, 1981 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Startup, Bill. The Kaikoura UFOs, n.d. (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Story, Ronald D. UFOs and the Limits of Science, 1981 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Strieber, Whitley. Communion, 1988 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Strieber, Whitley. Confirmation, 1998 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Material removed from: Tambling, Richard. Flying Saucers, 1992 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Rommel, Jr., Kenneth M., "Operation Animal Mutilation", 1980 June (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Rutland, Jonathan. "UFOs" [children's Book], 1987 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Smith, Marcia S., "The UFO Enigma", 1983 June 20 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Teets, Bob. "UFOs and Mental Health", 1997 (Box Series VIII-2)
- Bound volumes, 1989-1995; 6 vols. (Volume 1-6)
  Uncorrected proofs or galleys of books on UFOs. Filed at the end of the collection.
  - Out There: The Government's Secret Quest for Extraterrestrials. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1990; Blum, Howard
  - Close Encounters of the Fourth Kind: Alien Abduction, UFOs, and the Conference at M.I.T. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1995; Bryan, C.D.B.
  - Report on Communion: An Independent Investigation of and Commentary on Whitley Strieber's Communion." New York: William Morrow and Company, Inc., 1989; Conroy, Ed
  - Crash at Corona: The U.S. Military Retrieval and Cover-Up of a UFO. New York: Paragon House, 1992, Friedman, Stanton T. and Don Berliner
  - Top Secret / MAJIC. New York: Marlowe and Co., 1996; Friedman, Stanton T.
  - The Gulf Breeze Sightings: The Most Astounding Multiple Sightings of UFOs in U.S. History. New York: William Morrow and Co., 1990; Walters, Ed and Frances Walters